TIFFANY HUEY

ortfolium.com/TiffanyHuey/portfolio

4 (402) 301-9586

San Diego, CA 92103

in tiffanyhuey

tiffanyannhuey

Versatile Web Developer with experience developing and managing complex e-commerce sites. Highly organized, independent, and conscientious coder able to adapt to changing priorities and maintain a strong work ethic with creativity and humor. Passionate about building beautiful, functional websites, including one that received a 2018 Blades Award for Most Improved Website.

Awards

Mivite Shout Out

July 2018

Recognized by the company for performance on Power Reviews API integration for Westpoint Home LLC

Skills

Web Technologies & Frameworks

HTML5

CSS3 (SASS/LESS, Bootstrap)

JavaScript/ jQuery

Xcode

Ruby on Rails

Sinatra

Swift

Database and ORM

MySQL

PostgreSQL

ActiveRecord

Versioning and Other Tools

Git

Bitbucket

Testing and Web Debug Tools

Chrome Developer Tools

Firebug/Firefox Developer Tools

RSpec

Jasmine

CMS and E-Commerce Platforms

Wordpress

Miva Merchant

Core Competencies

Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)

Test Driven Development (TDD)

REST/CRUD Applications

Agile Development

Project Management

Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Volunteering

San Diego RailsBridge Chapter Volunteer Teacher April 2017

Lead a workshop for underrepresented demographics to delve into programming language concepts; build a web application using Ruby on Rails framework

Projects

Borsheims Lead MAP Developer

April 2018 to Current

Primary developer for Borsheims for all ongoing projects after site launch, including share/email wish list functionality, storefront redesign, and inventory report generation

Taylor Swift Official Merchandise Tour Lookbook Page

Oct. 2017

Build lookbook page for store.taylorswift.com to showcase Reputation Merchandise using HTML , CSS, and Miva LSK

RiSE

March 2017

RiSE is a mobile alarm application that leverages the Apple Maps API to calculate one's wakeup time based on three factors: (1) desired arrival time, (2) commute time (variable) and (3) time required for one's morning routine. It also has standard alarm functionality. Technologies: Swift. Xcode. Core Data

Employment

Miva Web Developer June 2017 to Current

Build solutions for mid-to-enterprise level e-commerce websites using the Miva software platform. Collaborate with a team of Web Developers and Account Managers to manage and deliver up to 30 concurrent website projects in a timely manner. Directly interface with clients, provide recommendations for improving store's performance and functionality, and write clean, functional code that is scalable and maintainable.

- Improve client businesses by building custom e-commerce features and pioneer new projects such as multi-add-to-cart functionality with Miva native suggestive search.
- Work with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, phpMyAdmin, MySQL, PHP, and Miva's Limited Source Kit API
- Build front-end webpages from Photoshop mockups, debug and resolve website issues, data & system analysis, and construct feeds per client specifications.
- Implement third party integrations, including custom ERPs, Power Reviews, SearchSpring, Wordpress, and Mailchimp
- Optimize websites for SEO, updates to .htaccess and website files to reduce page load time

Rosemont Media Web Project Manager June 2015 to Jan. 2017

Oversee all new website build projects and serve as main point-of-contact for clients throughout the website development life cycle. Coordinated project needs across multiple departments, including sales, design, content writers, and development in order to launch sites within expected timeframes. Identified key website traffic areas and SEO optimization opportunities to improve website performance metrics.

- Implement client requests via Wordpress backend and leverage telecommunication conference tools to demonstrate Wordpress capabilities to end-users
- Head all website project development and client status meetings; establish and meet project milestones; iteratively
 identify areas for project development
- Provide build documentation and QA testing for website in development across all devices and browsers, and track issues with development team
- Prepare sitemap and .htaccess files in conjunction with website launches and monitor/update links using Google Webmaster tools

Rightlook Creative

lan. 2015 to lune 2015

Project Manager

Manage web design and marketing branding projects (print, design, and video production) within a full-service marketing and digital advertising agency serving a broad range of industries. Handle a high volume of projects with shifting priorities and facilitate communications between clients and a team of designers, content writers, marketers, and videographers. Negotiate contracts and communicate project progress and milestones with all parties (clients, design/production team, and vendors).

- · Understand the design process from conceptualization and brainstorming to a meticulous eye for detail in final stages
- Consult with clients on their marketing/advertising needs; prepare Creative Briefs and other supporting documents the design team/production team will require
- Utilize industry standard project management tools to organize all project tasks and change orders; manage master design and print calendar
- Manage all purchasing activities: (research vendors and freelancers, negotiate pricing and terms with vendors, place orders, receive products, ship products and coordinate PO's and billing with accounting department)
- Update and document operational and project management SOPs, define best practices criteria

Computer Market Research

June 2013 to Jan. 2015

Project Manager

Oversee successful delivery of Co-op/MDF marketing solutions to large-scale distributors. Responsible for translating client's business rules into design specifications and serve as main point-of-contact. Oversee all aspects of development, from planning, software development implementation, to quality assurance testing to ensure that scope requirements are completely fulfilled.

- Proactively drive project status meetings, prepare and maintain project milestones, schedules, action items, and issues
 and identify and/or build proper SLAs.
- Draft contracts and manage invoicing and payment processes between clients and the accounts receivables department
- Demonstrate leadership and team building track record, strong project management skills, and ability to develop and
 leverage effective working relationships as the Project Manager, operate across a dynamic IT environment encompassing
 all levels of management within IT and its partners.
- Identify and document Project Management best practices for Continuous Improvement environment.

Education

Dev Bootcamp

Nov. 2016 to April 2017

Full Stack Web Development
Complete 1000+ hours of coding in a 19-week immersive, full stack web development program. Languages and frameworks
learned: Git workflow/version control, Ruby, JavaScript (object-oriented JavaScript, jQuery, and AJAX), Test-Driven Development
(RSpec and Jasmine), Sinatra, Ruby on Rails.

University of San Diego B.B.A Marketing B.A French Sept. 2006 to May 2010